Gerald Scott fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Gerald Scott fonds
1990 - 1991
F-167
Q104470725
11 sound recordings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION Fonds includes 22 audio cassettes (originals and copies).
Scott, Gerald
Gerry Scott received a Master's degree from SFU in 1991 for his thesis entitled Beyond Equality: British Columbia New Democrats and Native Peoples, 1961-1979. In the preface to his thesis, Scott writes, "My interest in the evolution of the political relationships between British Columbia New Democrats and the aboriginal peoples of the province was first aroused in 1974. At that time I was working as a researcher for the government caucus and I undertook preparation of background papers on aboriginal land claims for the consideration of caucus members. In the 1970s and 1980s I continued to be involved in many of the issues under examination in this thesis through my work as Executive Assistant to Skeena MP Jim Fulton and as Provincial Secretary of the NDP during the years of Bob Skelly's leadership."
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on its provenance.
The fonds consists of the audiocassettes for eleven interviews conducted by Gerry Scott for his thesis.
The materials were arranged by the archivist alphabetically by interview subject.
New Democratic Party of British Columbia; Sound recordings; Textual records; First nations; Politics
The tapes were donated to the archives.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Archives and Records Management Department held the tapes without any documentation linking them to Scott's thesis.
Also see Gerry Scott thesis.
There are no privacy restrictions on the interviews, however, for preservation reasons access to the sound recordings is restricted due to the age and fragility of the storage medium (cassette tape). The Archives will provide access only through digitizing the originals. As of October 2012 only one of the interviews (item 1, Dave Barrett) has been digitized. Consult the reference archivist for more information about accessing these records.
The creator of the interviews (Gerald Scott) has retained copyright ownership to the works. Please consult the reference archivist for more information about permission to use copyrighted material.
A file list is available. An abstract of Gerry Scott's thesis is available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
- Barrett, Dave; Vancouver, 30 November 1990; F-167-0-0-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3760, Audio cassette OBJ-3761, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3782, Webdav: virtual stacks OBJ-4020)
  published
  Barrett, Dave; Sound recordings
  Open
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-1.1 orig., F-167-item1.
- Berger, Tom; Vancouver, 1 February 1991; F-167-0-0-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3762, Audio cassette OBJ-3763, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3978, Webdav: virtual stacks OBJ-4020)
  Berger, Tom; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-2.1 orig., F-167-item2.
- Howard, Frank; Vancouver, 27 November 1990; F-167-0-0-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3764, Audio cassette OBJ-3765)
  Howard, Frank; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-3.1 orig., F-167-item3.
- Levi, Norman; Vancouver, 14 November 1990; F-167-0-0-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3766, Audio cassette OBJ-3767)
  Levi, Norman; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-4.1 orig., F-167-item4.
- Macdonald, Alex; Vancouver, 29 November 1990; F-167-0-0-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3768, Audio cassette OBJ-3769)
  Macdonald, Alex; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-5.1 orig., F-167-item5.
- Sanders, Doug; Vancouver, 30 October 1990; F-167-0-0-0-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3770, Audio cassette OBJ-3771, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3978, Webdav: virtual stacks OBJ-4020)
  Sanders, Doug; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-6.1 orig., F-167-item6.
- Schreyer, Ed; Burnaby, 16 April 1991; F-167-0-0-0-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3772, Audio cassette OBJ-3773)
  Schreyer, Ed; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-7.1 orig., F-167-item7.
- Skelly, Bob; Ottawa, 8 March 1991; F-167-0-0-0-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-3774, Audio cassette OBJ-3775)
  Skelly, Bob; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-8.1 orig., F-167-item8.
- Watts, George; Vancouver, 13 December 1990; F-167-0-0-0-0-9 (Audio cassette OBJ-3776, Audio cassette OBJ-3777, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3978, Webdav: virtual stacks OBJ-4020)
  Watts, George; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-9.1 orig., F-167-item9.
- Williams, Bob; Vancouver, 12 December 1990; F-167-0-0-0-0-10 (Audio cassette OBJ-3778, Audio cassette OBJ-3779)
  Williams, Bob; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-10.1 orig., F-167-item10.
- Wilson, Bill; Vancouver, 10 January 1991; F-167-0-0-0-0-11 (Audio cassette OBJ-3780, Audio cassette OBJ-3781, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3978, Webdav: virtual stacks OBJ-4020)
  Wilison, Bill; Sound recordings
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-167-0-0-11.1 orig., F-167-item11.